centralized version control
distributed version control - git

git:
each computer store a full database, you don't need to connect to server to get a file or update a file.

server - reprository

         	computer1 - repository
database computer2 - repository
 	computer3 - repository

git three main states: committed, modified, staged

committed means that the data is safely stored in your local database
modified means that you have changed the file but have not committed it to your database yet.
staged means that you have marked a modified file in its current version to go into your next commit snapshot.